Katharine Abraham, an economics professor, was chatting with her hairdresser about retirement plans.
经济学教授凯瑟琳·亚伯拉罕当时正和她的理发师聊着退休计划。
The economist said she plans to continue working because she wants to.
这位经济学家说，她打算继续工作，因为她自己想工作。
The hairdresser agreed but for a different reason: She needs the money.
理发师也说自己会继续工作，但理由不同：她需要钱。
Both scenarios are contributing to a big increase in the number of people in the U.S. working into their 70s.
这两种情况都在促使美国工作到七十多岁的人数大幅增加。
Over the past 20 years, the share of Americans working in their 70s has risen from less than 10% to nearly 15%.
在过去20年里，七十多岁仍在工作的美国人所占比例已从不到10%升至近15%。
In addition to people being healthier and living much longer, economists say that a combination of financial considerations such as years of slow rise in real wages and a shift away from traditional pensions in the private sector is among the reasons people delay retirement.
经济学家表示，除了人们更加健康、寿命长得多之外，多种财务考虑因素共同作用也是人们推迟退休的原因之一，比如实际工资多年来增长缓慢，以及私营部门逐渐放弃传统养老金。
The decline of manufacturing and the increase in the number of people working in less labor-intensive occupations also have contributed to the trend, says Abraham, who researches work and retirement decisions of older Americans.
亚伯拉罕研究美国老年人的工作与退休决策，她说，制造业的衰落以及从事劳动密集程度较低职业的人数增加，也促成了这一趋势。
“Which matters more depends on what your history up until that point has been in the type of work you’re doing,” Abraham says.
“哪个因素更重要，取决于你到那时为止在所从事的这类工作中有着怎样的经历，”亚伯拉罕说。
The overall trend is hitting Americans of all different levels of educational attainment, although the percentages vary by category.
这一总体趋势正波及各种受教育程度的美国人，不过比例因类别而异。
The share of Americans with bachelor’s degrees who were working into their 70s reached nearly 20% in 2018.
2018年，拥有学士学位的美国人中，工作到七十多岁的人所占比例达到近20%。
For those with a high school degree or less, the proportion of those working in their 70s had risen to around 10%, while those with some college education were in the middle at around 15%.
在高中及以下学历的人中，七十多岁仍在工作的比例已升至10%左右，而上过大学但没有拿到学士学位的人则居中，约为15%。
Martin Neil Baily, an economist who is leading a research project on retirement security, notes that quitting a career can lead to feelings of isolation and loneliness, particularly for men.
马丁·尼尔·贝利是一位经济学家，正在主持一项关于退休保障的研究项目。他指出，放弃职业生涯可能会让人产生孤立感和孤独感，男性尤其如此。
He suggests that many college-educated workers are choosing to stay in the labor force more for social benefits than for financial reasons.
他认为，许多受过大学教育的劳动者选择留在劳动力队伍中，更多是为了社交方面的好处，而不是出于经济原因。
They’re also more likely to be in professional occupations where they tend to enjoy their work more.
他们也更有可能从事专业性职业，在这类职业中往往更享受自己的工作。
Workers in more physical jobs, meanwhile, may be more likely to look forward to retiring, Baily says, suggesting those who stay on are more likely doing so for financial reasons.
贝利说，另一方面，工作对体力要求更高的劳动者可能更盼着退休，这说明他们当中仍坚持工作的人更有可能是出于经济原因才这样做。